자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
이건 진짜 총이야
어떻게 쓰는지도 알아
This is a real gun,
and I know how to use it.
설마 쓰고 싶진 않으시겠죠
You don't wanna do this.
- 아니, 진짜 총이라니까!
- 아줌마!
- No, it's a real gun! No!
- Lady!
쏘면 어찌될지도 아주 잘 알아
I know how it works, too.
안 돼, 이러지 마!
No, don't do!
안 돼, 안 돼!
No, no, no, no!
- 얼른 나가자!
- 잠깐, 일은 하고 가야지!
- Let's get outta here!
- Wait. We gotta do the thing.
- 무슨 일?
- 그림, 그림 말이야!
- What thing?
- The thing, the painting!
그 정도면 충분해, 가자!
Okay, that's good enough!
Let's go!
MONK Season 4 Epi. 8
Mr. Monk and Little Monk
토니 샬롭
(에이드리안 몽크 役)
트레일러 하워드
(나탈리 티거 役)
제이슨 그레이 스탠포드
(랜달 디셔 경위 役)
테드 리바인
(리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감 役)
딕테이션
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
싱크편집
윤선영(seedyun@nate.com)
한글번역
한상희(fithelestre@sanori.net)
번역수정
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
한글교정
이미란(lmr0412@nate.com)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON USA: 2005/08/26
좋아요, 이놈은 괜찮고
Okay, this one is okay.
- 몽크와 꼬마 몽크 -
이놈은 상태 좋네요
This one is good.
몽크 씨, 정말
씻을 필요 없다니까요
Mr. Monk, really,
you don't have to wash them.
재활용될 거란 말이에요
They're just gonna get recycled.
모두 한데 집어넣고
부숴버릴 거라고요
They're just gonna
get all smushed together.
그 말이 맞을지도 모르죠
이건 여전히 끈적거려요
You may be right.
This one's still sticky.
다시 씻어야겠네요
We'll wash that again.
나가서 누군지 볼래요?
Are you gonna get that?
나탈리?
Natalie?
안녕하세요
Hello.
몽크 씨
Mr. Monk.
옛 친구라면서
어떤 여자 분이 오셨어요
There's someone here to see you.
She says she's an old friend.
셰리 져드라는데요?
Sherry Judd?
셰리가...
Sherry...
여기 왔어요?
She's here?
뭣 때문이래요?
What does she want?
저야 모르죠, 누군데요?
I don't know. Who is she?
중학교 2학년 때 알고
지냈던 친구예요
Someone I knew
in the eighth grade.
사과하러 온 건가요?
Is she here to apologize?
저야 모르죠
I don't know.
너무 늦어서 별 볼일 없다고
말해줘요
Well, tell her it's
too little too late.
아니, 잠깐! 잠깐요, 음...
No, wait! Wait, uh...
트루디 얘길 해 주세요
Tell her about Trudy.
저 트루디랑 결혼했다고요
Tell her that I married Trudy.
트루디가 절 사랑했다고 말해 주세요
Tell her Trudy loved me.
트루디가 얼마나 미인이었는지도요
Tell her how pretty Trudy was.
잠깐잠깐
Well, wait.
트루디랑 잤다는 것도 말해줘요
Tell her Trudy and I
went all the way.
몽크 씨, 이분은 도움이
필요해서 오신 것 같아요
Mr. Monk, I think
she needs your help.
숙제 때문에요?
With her homework?
아뇨, 사건이죠
No, with a case.
이제 다 큰 어른이잖아요
We're all grown up now.
아, 예, 그러네요
Oh, yeah. Right.
셰리
Sherry?
안녕, 나, 에이드리안 몽크야
Hello. It's, I'm Adrian Monk.
에이드리안...
Adrian, you...
멋있어졌구나
you look great.
아, 아마 날 기억 못 하겠지
Um, you probably don't
even remember me.
저 사람이 트루디야?
Is that Trudy?
미인이네
She was beautiful.
나탈리가 그간 사정을 다 말해 줬어
정말 안됐어
Natalie told me what happened.
I'm so sorry.
고마워
Thank you.
우린 같이 잤어
We went all the way.
앉으시겠어요?
Please, why don't you have a seat?
뭐라도 좀 드릴까요?
Can I offer you anything?
사다 놓은 생수하고 또...
Um, we have bottled water.
And, uh...
생수밖에 없네요
pushing the bottled water.
괜찮아요, 고맙습니다
I'm fine. Thanks.
어디서부터 시작하지?
Where to begin?
시애틀에 살고 있었는데
I've been living in Seattle.
- 우린 3년 전에 이사 왔어
- 우리?
- We just moved back three years ago.
- We?
- 아, 남편이랑 나
- 아하
Oh, my husband and I.
이름은 마이클이야
Michael.
이혼한 지 얼마 안 됐어
We're recently divorced.
이런, 정말 안 됐구나
Oh, I'm so sorry.
아니, 아주 잘된 일이었어
정말로 말이야
No, no, it's, it's for the best.
Believe me.
그래서 나랑 가정부 글래디스
둘이서만 살게 됐거든
So it's just been me
and my housekeeper Gladys.
그래서 여기 찾아온 거야
That's why I'm here.
일요일 밤에 누군가가 침입했어
Sunday night someone broke in.
글래디스가 자다가 깼나 본데
I guess Gladys woke up.
몸싸움이 벌어진 게 틀림없었어
There must have been a fight.
그러다가...
And, um...
- 글래디스가 살해당했어
- 세상에
- he killed her.
- Oh, my god.
- 넌 다친 데 없고?
- 응, 집에 없었거든
- Are you okay?
- No, I wasn't home.
에이드리안
Adrian...
가족이라곤 글래디스밖에 없었어
I'm the only family Gladys had.
그 사람을 위해
법의 심판을 내리고 싶어
I just want justice for her.
최고에게 이 사건을
꼭 맡겼으면 싶어서
I want to make sure that
the best people are working on this.
주위에 물어보니 다들
너보고 천재라더라고
And I've been asking around,
and everyone says you're a genius.
물론 난 이미 알고 있었지만 말이야
But, of course, I already knew that.
에이드리안은 어렸을 때
곤경에 빠진 저를 구해 줬어요
Adrian, um, helped me
out of a jam when we were kids.
- 한 30년 전쯤이었죠
- 1972년 4월 12일이야
- About, uh, 30 years ago.
- It was April 12, 1972.
그걸 기억해?
You remember?
난 날짜만 기억나
I only remember the date.
그리고 당사자들이 뭘 입었는지랑
And what everybody wore.
뭘 말했는지, 뭘 했는지만 기억나
And what everybody said.
And what everybody did.
여기 있군요
1972년도 웨스트오버 중학교
Here it is.
Westover junior high 1972.
나탈리, 열지 말아요
Natalie, don't open that.
나탈리, 제자리에 돌려놔요
명령이에요
Natalie, put that back.
I command you.
셰리 져드
Sherry Judd
셰리, 너무 귀여웠네요
Sherry, you were so cute.
- 자, 몽크 씨는 어디 있어요?
- 나탈리, 덮지 못해요
- Okay, now, where is Mr. Monk?
- Natalie, just close the book.
말 들어요, 나탈리, 나탈리
I mean it, Natalie, Natalie.
그래, 됐어요
Okay, that's it.
당신은 해고예요
You're fired.
방금 해고했어
She's fired.
아니, 이게 어떻게 나야
No, that couldn't be me.
에이드리안 몽크라고
적혀 있는데요
It says Adrian Monk.
에이드리안
Adrian.
엄마, 다들 쳐다보잖아요
Mom, everyone's watching.
점심 여기 있다
Here's your lunch.
딱 우리가 좋아하는 식대로
작은 조각 10개로 잘랐지
It's cut into ten little squares
just the way we like it.
그리고 구급상자
And your first aid kit.
- 그리고 세면 가방
- 엄마
- And your toiletry bag.
- Mom...
나중엔 다 엄마가 고마울 거다
You'll thank me later.
명심해라
음식은 남이랑 나눠 먹지 말고
Remember, don't share
your food with anyone.
비상구 가까이에 앉도록 해
Sit near the fire doors.
3시 4분에 데리러 오겠다
귤색 블라우스를 입고 있을 거야
I'll pick you up at 3:04.
I'll be wearing an orange blouse.
엄마, 저도 엄마 얼굴은 알아요
Mom, I know what you look like.
별일 없을 거예요
I'll be fine.
사랑해요, 엄마
I love you, mom.
- 무슨 짓이냐?
- 죄송해요
- What are you doing?
- Right, sorry.
저기 와, 쟤 꼬락서니가 꼭
에디 문스터처럼 우습지 않니
Here he comes.
He's like the real-life Eddie Munster.
- 듣겠다, 얘
- 무슨 소린지도 모를걸
- He can hear you.
- He won't even know what it means.
TV도 안 놓고 산다고 들었어
I heard they don't even have a TV.
형은 집에 틀어박혀
절대 안 나온다더라
I heard his brother
never comes out of the house.
사전을 외우라고 시키기도 한대
I heard they have
to memorize the dictionary.
한 달에 알파벳 하나씩 말이야
One letter per month.
하루에 네 번씩
샤워한다고도 들었어
I heard that they take
four showers a day.
아, 안녕, 셰리
Oh, hi, Sherry.
네, 네가 권해 준 로큰롤 음반
고마웠다고 인사하고 싶어
I, uh, wanted to thank you for
recommending that Rock & Roll record.
정말 근사하더라
It was very groovy.
권한 적 없는데?
I didn't recommend anything.
권해 줬어
Yes, you did.
어제 레드 제플린 티셔츠를
입고 있었잖아
You were wearing a Led Zeppelin
T-shirt yesterday,
그 그룹 판을 추천한다는 거나
마찬가지지
which is the same thing
as recommending them.
그, 그래서 나가서
그 판을 사 왔어
So, uh, I went out,
and I bought their record.
뭐더라...
The, uh...
"천국으로 가는 계단"?
Stairway up to Heaven?
어때?
What did you think?
글쎄, 사실 난 아직 못 들어 봤어
Well, you know, I haven't
actually listened to it yet.
집에 턴테이블이 없거든
We don't have a record player.
아마 무지 좋을 거야
I assume it's excellent.
나한텐, 음, 근사했어
I mean, uh, groovy.
그래, 표지를 보면 알지
정말 근사해 보이더라고
Yes, you can tell from the cover.
They look so groovy.
이만 가야겠어
Well, I gotta go.
항상 자물쇠를
0으로 돌려놓는구나
You always turn your lock back to zero.
눈여겨봤어
나도 그러거든
I noticed that.
I do that too.
그렇게 놔두면 나중에
다시 따기 쉽지
So later it's easier to open.
사실 우리 둘은 공통점이 많아
Actually, there are a lot
of things we have in common.
"에이드리안 몽크와
셰리 져드의 공통점"
"Things Adrian Monk and
Sherry Judd have in common."
목록까지 만들었어?
You made a list?
첫째, 사물함이 바로 옆에 맞붙어 있다
One, our lockers are
right next to each other.
둘째, 둘 다 "패티 듀크 쇼"를 좋아한다
Two, we both like the Patty Duke show.
비록 패티가 사촌이면서 쌍둥이라며
1인 2역을 하면서
Even though she has to be lying
because they're supposed
to be identical cousins,
생물학적으로 말도 안 되는
거짓말을 하지만...
which is biologically impossible.
셋째, 개근 기록을 갖고 있다
에, 그리고, 넷째...
Three, perfect attendance records.
And, uh, four...
둘 다 봄 무도회에
같이 갈 상대가 없다
Neither of us has a date
to the spring fling.
어떻게 알았어?
How do you know that?
어쩌다 한 주 일정을
적어둔 수첩을 봤어
I happened to catch a glimpse
of your weekly planner.
그날 저녁에 애 본다고
일정을 적어놨더라고
And I noticed that you have a babysitting
job lined up for that evening.
내가 잘못 알았다면 모르지만
난 틀린 적이 없거든
Unless I'm wrong, which,
you know, I'm not.
- 안녕, 셰리
- 안녕, 지미
- Hey, Sherry.
- Hey, Jimmy.
- 미술 수업 가는데 모델 해 줄래?
- 그거 재밌겠다
I'm gonna art class.
You wanna be my model? / Yeah, cool.
잘 가, 에이드리안
Good-bye, Adrian.
안녕
Bye.
그래, 도와줄게
Yes, I will help you.
몽크 씨가 어릴 때는 어땠어요?
What was he like as a kid?
지금이랑 거의 비슷했죠
Pretty much the same.
주의 깊고 똑똑하고
Careful, smart.
슬픈 얼굴이었어요
Sad.
사람은 변하지 않는 법이에요
I don't think people change, really.
적어도 변하는 걸 보진 못했네요
At least I've never seen it.
제 남편이 변할까 싶어
10년을 기다렸죠
I waited ten years
for my husband to change.
몽크 씨?
Mr. Monk?
몽크 씨, 얼른 건너오세요
Mr. Monk, let's come over here.
이상하군
Strange.
손가락 지문은 찍혔는데
손바닥이 안 찍혔어요
Fingerprints, but no palm prints.
두 놈이 들어왔군요
There were two of them.
가정부 때문에 놀랐어요
The housekeeper surprised them.
몸싸움이 있었고
There was a struggle.
이 경보기를 눌렀지만
She pushes this alarm.
머리를 맞고 여기 쓰러졌어요
She hits her head and falls here.
이 그림 말이야
This painting...
값나가는 거야?
is it valuable?
가치는 별로 없지만 내겐 소중해
Not really, except to me.
우리 증조모님이시거든
It's my great grandmother.
어떤 놈이 뭐 하러 이런 짓을 할까?
Why would someone do something
like that?
집안에 스프레이 페인트가 있어?
Did you have spray paint in the house?
아니
No.
그럼 놈들이 가지고 왔겠군요
So they must have brought it with them.
고마워요
Thank you.
이건 가정부의 피야
This is the housekeeper's blood.
그럼 가정부를 죽인 다음에
그림을 훼손한 거네
So they defaced the painting
after they killed her,
경보가 울린 후라는 건데
이런 짓에 모든 걸 걸어?
after the alarm sounded.
They risked everything?
증조모 얼굴을 망가뜨리려고
They risked life in prison
to deface your great grandmother?
평생 감옥에서
썩을 위험을 무릅쓰다니
놈들이 여기 온 목적이 이거 같아
I think that's why they were here.
이걸 하려고 말이야
To do this.
- 안경이랑 콧수염을 그리려고요?
- 턱수염도 조금
- To draw glasses and a mustache?
- And a little goatee.
증조모라고 하셨죠?
She was your great grandmother?
어떤 분인지 말씀해 주세요
Tell me about her.
뵌 적도 없는 분이죠
I never met her.
유명한 여성 참정권론자셨대요
She was a famous suffragette.
투표권을 얻으려 투쟁하시다
감옥에도 가셨지요
She went to jail for the right to vote.
뭔가 의사 표시를 한 건지도 몰라요
정치적인 주장 같은 거요
Maybe they were making a statement.
Like a political thing.
그러니까 가택 침입해서
여자를 때려죽이고
You mean they broke into the house,
and they beat a woman to death,
그림을 훼손한 게 수정헌법 19조에
불만이 있어서였다는 건가?
then defaced the painting because they
had trouble with the 19th amendment?
네
Yes.
아, 그건 좀 아니겠군요
I mean, no.
정말 수수께끼네요
It's a mystery.
괜찮아요, 집주인입니다
It's okay. It's my house.
- 셰리
- 마이클?
Sherry? / Michael?
당신 여기 어떻게 들어왔어?
How did, how did you get in?
아직 우리 집이잖아, 셰리
It's still my house, Sherry.
- 적어도 문서상으로는
- 거짓말 마
- At least technically.
- That is not true.
맘대로 들어오면 안 돼
마이클, 우리...
You can't just come over,
Michael, it's...
- 그렇게 합의했잖아
- 뉴스에 나와서 안 와볼 수 없었어
- it's in the agreement.
- It was on the news. I had to come.
글래디스 일은 안됐어
진심이야
Sorry about Gladys. I really am.
다친 덴 없어?
Are you okay?
- 사건 때 여기 있었어?
- 언니를 만나러 샌디에이고에 갔었어
- Were you here?
- I was in San Diego visiting my sister.
맞아, 그건 나도 알았어
That's right. I knew that.
스토틀마이어 반장님
제 전남편 마이클 노플릿이에요
Um, captain Stottlemeyer,
this is my ex-husband Michael Norfleet.
예, 이미 노플릿 씨랑 얘기했습니다
Yes, we've already spoken to Mr. Norfleet.
에이드리안 몽크랑
나탈리 티거입니다
Adrian Monk and Natalie Teeger.
- 몽크? 중학교 동창이라는?
- 그렇습니다
- Monk? From junior high?
- That's right.
셰리가 당신 얘기 많이 해 줬습니다
Sherry told me all about you.
체육 수업에 단 한 번도
참석 안 했던 사연을요
About how you never took
a single gym class.
각서를 썼죠
I had a note.
원 세상에!
Oh, my god!
저런 짓도 해 놨어?
짐승 같은 놈들
They did that too? Animals.
- 도둑맞은 건 없고?
- 마이클, 제발 좀 가 줘
- Did they take anything?
- Michael, please just leave.
떠나 달라고 하지 않았습니까
Sir, she asked you to leave.
예, 알았어요, 간다고요
Yes, okay. I'm going.
하지만, 그러기 전에
But before I do,
우표 한 장 아낄까 싶네요
I figured I'd save myself a stamp.
여기 있어
매달 떼 주기도 정말 지긋지긋하군
Here you go.
Your monthly pound of flesh.
다음엔 우편으로 보내
Mail it next time.
우표 값은 낼 테니까
I'll pay for the stamp.
그래, 알았어
Yeah, well.
잘 해결되길 바라
Good luck on this.
또 기회 되면 보자고
See you around.
고마워
Thank you.
얼마나 벌었어?
How much do we have?
18달러 25센트
$18.25.
어떻게 알아?
How do you do that?
나도 몰라
I don't know.
좀 우습지 않니
댄스파티를 위해 모금하는 건데
It's kind of funny,
raising money for a dance
정작 우리 둘은 못 가잖아
that neither of us is going to.
저기, 레오
그거 돈 내고 먹어야 해
Uh, Leo, here's the thing,
you gotta pay for that.
뭐에 돈 낸다고?
Pay for what?
증거가 어디 있는데, 짝퉁 콜롬보?
Where's your evidence, Columbo?
레오, 티킷 교장 선생님께 이른다
농담 아니야
Leo, I'm telling principal Thicket.
I'm not kidding.
그러기만 해봐, 셰리
후회하게 될걸
You don't wanna do that, Sherry.
You'll be sorry.
난 한다면 해
I mean it.
돈 낼 거야, 안 낼 거야?
Are you gonna pay us or not?
레오, 정말 이른다!
농담 아니라니까!
Leo, I'm telling.
I'm serious!
여기 있어, 괜찮아
그냥 초콜릿 묻은 거니까
Here, it's okay.
It's only chocolate. Here.
고마워
Thanks.
물수건 챙겨다니는 게 좋겠어
You should carry these with you.
지난해부터 셰리의 집에서
일했던 사람들 명단이네
That's a list of people that have worked
at her house over the past year.
- 아는 이름 없나?
- 없어요
- Do you recognize anybody?
- No.
우리도 못 찾았어
Neither did we.
몽크, 나탈리랑 셰리가
아래층에서 기다립니다
Monk, Natalie and Sherry
are downstairs waiting for you.
아, 훼손된 그림을
박물관으로 가져간대요
Oh, yeah. They're taking
the painting to the museum.
제임스 더피라는 사람이 거기서
일하는데 복원 전문가랍니다
A guy named James Duffy works there.
He's a restoration expert.
- 자네도 같이 가나?
- 예
- What, you're going with?
- Yeah.
잘 지켜보게
Keep your eyes open.
예? 그게 무슨 말씀이세요?
What? What do you mean?
자네 친구라는 셰리 져드가
It's just that your friend, Sherry Judd,
2주 전에 백만 달러쯤 나가는
주택 소유자 보험을 들었다더군
just got a homeowner's policy
worth a million dollars two weeks ago.
- 참 시기적절 하지 않은가?
- 말도 안 됩니다
- That's pretty convenient, isn't it?
- Well, that's ridiculous.
보험을 타려고 자작극을 벌였다고요?
You think she did it herself
for the insurance?
셰리는 자기 말대로
샌디에이고에 있었어
No, no, she was in San Diego
like she said.
누군가를 고용했을지도 모르지
But she could've hired somebody.
- 아닙니다
- 아냐?
No. / No?
돈 같은 거 필요 없어요
She doesn't need the money.
이혼수당 수표를 봤는데
한 달에 2만 달러씩 받는다고요
I got a look at that alimony check.
She's getting 20 grand a month.
- 꽤 많은 돈이군
- 이해해 주시니 고맙군요
- That's a lot of dough.
- Thank you.
하지만, 몽크...
But Monk...
우린 부자들을 수도 없이
감옥에 처넣었네
you and I have put enough
rich people in jail
돈이 많아도 절대 만족하지
못하는 게 사람이야
to know that a lot of dough is
never enough.
항상 더 많은 돈을 원하지
They always want more.
셰리는 안 그래요
Not Sherry.
셰리를 잘 모르셔서
그러시는 겁니다
You don't know her.
뭐가 우스우세요?
What?
그냥... 자네가 여자에 대해
이런 식으로 말하는 게
It's just that I haven't heard you
talk about a woman like this...
정말 오랜만이라서
for a long time.
그 초콜릿들 어떻게 다 닦아냈어?
How did you get all that chocolate out?
엄마가 사물함에 여벌의 윗도리를
항상 갖다 놓게 시키거든
My mom makes me keep
a backup shirt in my locker.
저기, 셰리...
Listen, Sherry...
- 나, 난 네가 정말 좋...
- 안녕, 져드
- I, uh, I really like you...
- Hey, Judd.
여기
Here.
도와줄게
Let me help.
무슨 짓이야?
What are you doing?
티킷 선생님이 나보고
좀 더 신사답게 행동하라더라
Mr. Thicket said I have to act
more like a gentleman.
그리고선 바로 2주간 수업 끝나고
학교에 남아 있으라는 벌을 내리셨어
He said that just before
he gave me two weeks detention.
일러바쳐 줘서 참 고마워
Thanks for ratting me out.
그게, 레오, 파티 장식 위원회에서
만든 물건을 훔쳤으니까
Well, you know, Leo, you were
stealing from the decorating committee.
모든 사람이 이용할 물건을
도둑질한 거나 마찬가지라고, 얘
Man, which means that you were
really stealing from everybody.
진정하시지, 찰리 브라운
벌써 교훈은 잘 알아먹었어
Relax, Charlie Brown.
I learned a lesson.
다시는 도둑질 안 해
I'll never steal again.
이를테면 이런 짓은
절대 안 할 거야
For example, I'll never do this.
어, 야, 레오
그건 내 거야
Uh, hey, Leo. That's mine.
그만 돌려줄래?
Could you please give it back?
이걸 화장실에 절대절대
담그지도 않을 거고
And I would never ever
dip this into the toilet.
레오, 제발 그러지 마
화장실은 안 돼, 안 돼
Oh, Leo, please.
Not the toilet, not the toilet.
그만 해, 레오
남자답게 굴어
Come on, Leo.
Be cool, man.
네가 상관할 일이 아냐, 지미
This is none of your business, Jimmy.
이미 세상은 나쁜 생각들로
넘치고 넘친단 말이야
I'm just saying there's already
enough bad vibes in the world.
거기다 또 하날
추가할 필요는 없잖아
You don't have to add to it.
그만 돌려줘
Come on.
Give it back.
믹 재거라면 어떻게 했겠어?
(롤링 스톤즈의 리드 보컬)
What would Mick Jagger do?
남자답게 돌려주지 않았겠어?
He'd give it back, wouldn't he?
여기 있어
이걸로 끝이 아냐
Here. This isn't over.
근데 댄스파티 제목이 뭐야?
So what's the name of that dance?
"봄날 기분 내기"
The spring fling?
정말 멍청한 제목이네
That sounds stupid.
그래도 가고 싶으면 같이 가자
But if you wanna go, I'll go.
그래, 그거 멋지겠다
Yeah, that would be cool.
- 괜찮아?
- 괜찮아
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
정말 괜찮아?
나탈리가 들게 했어도 됐는데
Are you sure? Because I could
get Natalie to carry it.
아, 안녕하세요
Oh, hello.
복원 전문가 제임스 더피랑
약속했는데요
We have an appointment with
James Duffy. Art restoration.
- 예, 주 전시실에서 만나실 겁니다
- 고마워요
Sure. He'll meet you
in the main gallery. / Thank you.
- 몽크 씨, 충고 좀 해도 될까요?
- 그럼요
Mr. Monk, can I give you
some advice? / Yeah.
그저 친구로서 충고하는 거예요
And I'm only saying this to you
as a friend.
데이트를 해본 사람으로서요
As someone who's dated...
그것도 많이요
a lot.
왜 그래요?
What?
와인이 엎질러졌어요
Some wine spilled.
어디에요?
Where?
저기요
Over there.
그냥 그림이잖아요
It's a painting.
저걸 보고 있으니 미치겠는데요
It's driving me a little crazy.
그럼 보지 말아요
Then don't look at it.
셰리 말인데요
It's about Sherry.
- 몽크 씨를 계속 눈여겨봤는데...
- 안 볼 수가 없네요
- I've been watching you, and I...
- I can't not look.
아마 고쳐 그릴 수 있겠죠
만날 사람이 복원 전문가랬죠?
Maybe they could fix it.
This guy we're seeing restores art, right?
몽크 씨 / 그냥 위에다
덧그릴 수 있을지도 몰라요
Mr. Monk. / Maybe he could
just paint over it.
- 이렇게 돌려세우고...
- 그림은 신경 꺼요
- Turn that up.
- Forget about the painting.
셰리한테 데이트 신청해요
I think you should ask her out.
- 같이 저녁식사 하라고요
- 셰리요? 안 돼요
- Take her to dinner.
- Sherry? No.
- 할 수 없어요
- 할 수 있어요
- No, I can't.
- Yes, you can.
- 원하는 줄 다 알아요
- 내가요?
- I know you want to.
- I do?
그래요, 원하잖아요
Yes. You want to.
이것만은 내 말 믿어요
Trust me on this.
트루디는 어쩌고요?
난 유부남이라고요
What about Trudy?
I'm a married man.
몽크 씨, 이건 데이트라기보다
Mr. Monk, it's not really a date.
소꿉친구로서
그냥 안부 주고받는 거예요
You're old friends, right?
You're just catching up.
셰리는 몽크 씨를 좋아해요
Mr. Monk, she likes you.
- 그럴 리가 없어요
- 어째서요?
- Uh, there's no way.
- Why not?
날 잘 아니까요
She knows me.
잠시만 이렇게 생각해 봐요
Just think about this for one second.
이 도시에서 활약하는
사립탐정이 2백 명도 넘는데
There are over 200 private
detectives in this city.
굳이 당신을 찾아왔잖아요?
But she came to you, didn't she?
몽크 씨를 좋아하는 거예요
She likes you.
두 번 얘기 않겠다, 져드
I'm not gonna ask you again, miss Judd.
저 사물함을 열어라
I want you to open that locker.
이건 말도 안 돼요, 티킷 교장 선생님
전 아무것도 안 훔쳤어요
This is crazy. Principal Thicket,
I didn't take anything.
사물함을 열어라
Open the locker.
- 무슨 일이야?
- 다과 판매 수익금이 없어졌는데
- What's going on?
- Somebody stole the bake sale money.
익명으로 쓴 쪽지가
티킷 선생님한테 왔대
Mr. Thicket got an anonymous note.
누가 썼는지는 몰라도
셰리 사물함에서 돈을 봤다는 거야
Whoever wrote it said they saw
the money in Sherry's locker.
그럴 리가 없어
That's impossible.
저... 제 것이 아닌데요
I... that's not mine.
제 것이 아니에요!
That's not mine!
어떻게 저게 여기 들어갔지?
How did that get in there?
돈은 어디 있느냐, 셰리?
Where's the money, Sherry?
몰라요, 맹세코 전 안 가져갔어요
I don't know.
I swear I didn't take it.
글쎄, 그럼 어떻게 이게
저 사물함 안에 들어갔을까?
Well, how did this get in there?
너 말고 자물쇠 번호 조합을
아는 사람이 있니?
Does anyone else know
your combination?
아뇨
No.
내 사무실로 가자
부모님 모시고 면담 좀 해야겠다
Let's go to my office.
I think we need to talk to your parents.
수업받으러 가라
다들 수업받으러 들어가!
Back to class.
Everybody, back to class!
이 그림 정말 좋아
I love this one.
사람 표정들 좀 봐
무슨 생각을 하는지 궁금한걸
Look at their faces.
I wonder what they're thinking.
여자가 남자를 죽이려고 하고 있어
She's planning to murder him.
뭐? / 광대버섯을 남자에게
먹이려고 하고 있거든
What? / She's about to feed him
amanita mushrooms.
하얀 작은 반점들을 보면 알 수 있어
You can tell by the little white spots.
치명적인 맹독이지
It's a deadly poison.
여자도 알고 그러는 건 아닐 거야
Maybe she doesn't know.
아니, 알고 그러는 거야
Oh, she knows.
남자한테 계속 맞았거든
He's been hitting her.
몸이 부어 있잖아
She's swollen.
왼쪽 눈이랑 팔에 든 멍을 봐
See the bruises on her arms
and her left eye.
자기가 뭘 하는지
아주 잘 알고 있어
She knows what she's doing.
정말 힘들겠다
Must be hard.
너처럼 사는 거
To be you.
모든 걸 다 알고 사는 거 말이야
To see everything.
아주 미치지
It's awful.
셰리
Sherry.
좀 궁금한 게 있는데 말이야
I was wondering...
여기 볼일 다 본 후에...
later when we're done here...
안 바쁘면...
if you're not too busy...
우리, 음, 그러니까, 그게...
maybe, um, we could, you know...
안녕하세요, 제임스 더피입니다
Hello. James Duffy.
제 조수가 그러는데 복원을
원하시는 유화가 있다고 해서...
Hi, my assistant told me you
have a canvas you need me to...
- 셰리 아니니?
- 그런데요
Sherry? / Yes.
지미 왜그너야
It's Jimmy Wagner.
지미라고?
Jimmy?
어머나 세상에
정말 믿기지가 않아!
Oh, my god. I don't believe this!
에이드리안, 믿어지니?
지미 왜그너야
Adrian, can you believe it?
It's Jimmy Wagner.
아직도 머리에 꽃 장식을
달고 다니는구나, 아주 예뻐
You still wear a flower in your hair.
You look great.
- 아냐, 너야말로 멋있어졌어
- 너야말로 예뻐
- Oh, no, you look great.
- You look great.
둘 다 멋지고 예쁜데요
They both look great.
아, 에이드리안 몽크 기억나니?
Oh, do you remember Adrian Monk?
그럼, 당연하지, 명탐정 에이드리안
항상 네가 활약한 기사 보고 있어
Yes, of course, Adrian, super sleuth.
I read about you all the time.
지미
Jimmy...
이쪽은 나탈리 티거
And Natalie Teeger.
- 안녕하세요
- 두 사람은...
Hi. / They're...
날 도와주러 왔어
이번 주에 끔찍한 일을 겪었거든
They're helping me out.
I've just had a terrible week.
우리 집에 누가 침입해서
가정부를 살해했어
Somebody broke into my house.
My housekeeper was killed.
그 사건 들었어
I heard about that.
정말 안됐다
당사자가 넌 줄은 전혀 몰랐어
I am so sorry.
I didn't realize that was you.
헷갈릴 만도 해, 가끔
셰리 노플릿이라는 이름을 쓰니까
Oh, it's confusing.
Sometimes I'm Sherry Norfleet.
4월에 이혼했어
I was divorced in April.
넌 결혼했니?
How about you?
나도 이혼했지
이런저런 일 참 많았어
Divorced. A lot of that going around.
그런데 성이 바뀌었네?
But you changed your name?
아, 우리 어머니가
15살 때 재혼하셨거든
Well, my mother remarried
when I was 15.
정말 멋있어졌다, 너
You really look great.
이제 환자를 한번 봐야겠는데
So I guess I should take
a look at the patient.
아, 바로 여기 있어
Oh, right over here.
홀치기 염색한 티셔츠만 입더니
참 많이 세련되어졌구나
You've come a long way
from tie-dyeing tee shirts.
여전히 주말이면 그런 옷을 입어
남들에겐 말하지 마
I still do that on the weekends too.
Don't tell anybody.
이 그림 기억나
I remember this painting.
너희 부모님 댁 식당에 걸려 있었지
This was in your parents' dining room.
- 맞아
- 잠깐만, 지미, 짐, 짐
- Yeah, that's right.
- Excuse me, Jimmy, Jim, Jim.
그 스프레이 페인트 말인데
특이한 점은 없어?
Is there anything peculiar
about that spray paint?
몇 가지 검사를 해 봐야겠지만
도포식 유성 에나멜 같은데
I'll have to run some tests, but
it feels like an oil-based spray enamel.
철물점 아무 데나 가면 구할 수 있어
You can get it at any hardware store.
어때, 의사 선생님?
So what do you think, doc?
제 얼굴을 되찾을 수 있을까?
Is she gonna make it?
괜찮아질 거야
내가 잘해 줄게
She'll be fine.
I'll take good care of her.
셰리, 혹시 바빠?
Sherry, are you busy?
내 작업실을 보여 주고 싶어
저기 모퉁이만 돌아가면 돼
I would love to show you my studio.
It's just around the corner.
나야 정말 기쁘지
I'd love that.
재미있을 것 같아
That sounds like fun.
몽크 씨도 멋져요
You look great.
셰리는 여기 있었고
Sherry was here.
모금함은 여기
Cash box was here.
레오가 들어와서
Leo comes in.
컵 케이크를 해치웠지
Put that cupcake down.
에이드리안 몽크 맞지?
Adrian monk, is that you?
댄스파티 끝나기 전까지는
여기 들어오면 안 돼
You're not allowed in here
until after the dance.
아, 여기 춤추러 온 거 아니에요
Oh, I'm not here for the dance.
누가 다과판매 수익금을
훔쳐갔는지 알아내려고 왔죠
I'm trying to figure out who stole
the money from the bake sale.
여자애가 훔쳤다며
They said it was that girl.
우등생 셰리 져드가 말이야
The honor student, Sherry Judd.
파티 후식으로 만든 거란다
I made these for the after-party.
여기 있으니 먹을만한지 말해 주렴
Here, tell me what you think.
여기, 이걸 집으렴
Here, here. Take this one.
초콜릿 칩이 10개 들었거든
딱 10개야
It has ten chocolate chips.
Exactly ten.
딱 네가 좋아할 구성이지
Just the way you like it.
정말 요리 솜씨가 좋으세요
리드스키 아주머니
You're an excellent cook, Mrs. Lidsky.
축복이기도 하고 저주이기도 하지
It's a gift and a curse.
몇 개 더 싸줄 테니 집에 가져가서
형이랑 나눠 먹으렴
Here, I'll send some more of these home
with you for you and your brother.
다과 판매하고 남은
상자를 몇 개 모아뒀지
I've got some boxes left
over from the bake sale.
파란색 아이싱 자국이네요
(과자에 묻히는 당의)
Blue icing.
이게 뭔데?
What is it?
실마리죠
It's a clue.
- 정말 안됐어요, 몽크 씨
- 아뇨, 셰리가 좋아해서 기뻐요
- I'm so sorry, Mr. Monk.
- No, I'm happy for her.
잘 어울리는 커플이 될 것 같네요
They seem like a great couple.
- 아직 커플은 아닌데요
- 그렇게 될 거예요
- Well, they're not a couple yet.
- They will be.
- 지미랑 데이트하러 갈 테니까
- 어떻게 알아요?
- She's gonna go out with him.
- How do you know?
사소한 것들을 눈여겨봤죠
셰리의 어조 같은 거
I notice little things,
like the way she said,
"그래, 같이 나가자"라든가
"Yes, I will go out with you."
지미의 손에 자기 전화번호를
적어 주면서
She wrote her phone number on his hand
27초씩이나 그 손을
놔주질 않더라고요
and didn't let go of his hand for 27 seconds.
나탈리
Natalie.
저 사람 장갑 봐요
Look at his gloves.
예, 어때서요?
Yeah, so?
손가락 부분이 없어요
No fingers.
셰리네 집 벽에 있던 손자국 기억나요?
Do you remember the handprint
on Sherry's wall?
범인이 오토바이를 탔을까요?
They were bikers?
그랬을 겁니다
They were bikers.
반장님
Captain...
작년에 셰리 져드의 집에서
일했던 사람들 명단 보셨습니까?
you know that list of all the people
who worked at Sherry judd's
house in the last year?
아니 / 오토바이 소유 등록자
명단이랑 대조해 봤는데요
No. / I cross-checked it against
registered motorcycle owners.
두 건이 나왔습니다
We got two hits.
아, 잘했어. 하나는 우리가 갖고
하나는 몽크에게 넘겨주게
Well, good, let's take one
and give one to Monk.
예, 어느 쪽을 넘길까요?
Yes, sir. Which one?
어느 쪽이냐는 중요치 않아
Doesn't matter.
그냥 하나 고르라고
Just pick one.
어-느-것-을-고-를-까-요-...
One potato, two potato, three
potato, four, five potato...
랜디, 사람이 죽었는데
뭐 하고 있나
Randy, a woman is dead.
예, 반장님
Yes, sir.
엄-마-한-테-물-어-볼-까-...
My mother told me to pick the...
저기요
Hey.
괜찮아요? 불편해 보이네요
You, okay?
You look uncomfortable.
- 그만 가죠
- 안 돼요, 몽크 씨, 전 괜찮아요
- Why don't we leave?
- No, Mr. Monk, I'm fine.
알았어요, 하지만
불편해지면 알려 줘요
Okay, but if you get uncomfortable,
you let me know.
- 뒤도 안 돌아보고 떠날 거예요
- 좋아요
- And we can just leave.
- Okay.
잠깐, 곧 불편해질 거 같다는
생각만 들어도 말해 줘요
Whoa, whoa, or if you feel like you're
about to get uncomfortable.
알았어요, 몽크 씨, 그냥 반장님을
불러서 해결하게 하지 그래요?
Okay, Mr. Monk, why don't we call
the captain and just let him handle this?
안 돼요! 안 돼요
No! No, no.
우리끼리도 할 수 있어요
We can do this.
- 누구한테 잘 보이고 싶은데요?
- 그런 사람 없어요
- Who are you trying to impress?
- Nobody.
- 셰리군요
- 아니에요
Sherry. / No.
나탈리, 난 사립탐정이니
이런 게 내 일이라고요
Natalie, I am a private detective.
This is what I do.
셰리 져드가 날 어떻게
생각하든 신경 안 써요
I don't care what Sherry Judd thinks of me.
특활 시간에 제 뒷자리에
앉아 있던 애였을 뿐이라고요
She's just a girl that sat
behind me in homeroom.
아가씨, 혼자유?
Hey, you alone?
아뇨, 이분과 같이 왔는데요
No, I'm with him.
혼자 온 게 맞구먼
So you're alone.
이것 보세요. 아저씨
이러지 말고 저리 가요
You know what, buddy?
You don't wanna do this.
Just back off.
안녕하세요? 트래비스랑
조지 뱁티스트를 찾고 있는데요
Hey, how you doing? We're looking for
Travis and George Baptiste.
- 들어본 적도 없는데요
- 알았어요, 그만 가죠
- Never heard of them.
- Okay, let's go.
거참 이상하네요
여기 죽치고 있는다던데
That's funny, because we heard
they're in here all the time.
웨이터, 저 사람...
Waiter. He's...
저 사람...
He's...
실례지만 여긴 금연인데요
Excuse me, sir.
There's no smoking.
괜찮아요, 뭐 담배 피우셔도 되겠죠
It's okay. He can smoke.
새로운 규칙을 정했지
등신 새끼는 화장실에 못 들어와
New rule, no spazzes in the bathroom.
그래, 등신 새끼를 보면 알려 줄게
Okay, if I see any spazzes,
I'll tell them.
넌 범생이 플립 윌슨 같은
쓸모없는 맹추야, 알기나 해?
You're a regular Flip Wilson,
you know that?
레오, 수익금은 어디 있어?
Where's the money, Leo?
무슨 소리야, 몽크?
존만이 같은 자식
What are you talking about, Monk?
Monk the punk.
네가 다과 판매 수익금을 훔쳤잖아
You took the money from the bake sale.
들고나가는 걸 보이지 않게
케이크 상자에 숨겼지
You put it in the cake box
so nobody would see you leaving with it.
이봐, 모금함은 이미
발견된 거 기억 안 나?
Hey, they found the empty
cash box, remember?
- 네 여자 친구 사물함에 있었잖아
- 잠겨 있었고
- It was in your girlfriend's locker.
- Which was locked.
- 네가 모함한 거잖아
- 어떻게?
- You framed her.
- How?
어디 말해 봐, 셰리 말곤 아무도
자물쇠 조합을 몰랐잖아
Tell me. She's the only one
who knows the combination.
어떻게 했는지는 모르겠어
I don't know how.
하지만, 네 짓이야
But you did it.
- 네가 범인이라고
- 내가 범인?
- You're the guy.
- I'm the guy?
널 네 사물함에 쑤셔 넣고
잠가버릴 위인은 되지
I'm the guy who's about to stuff you
in your own locker and lock the door.
우릴 찾으셨수?
You, uh, looking for us?
트래비스 뱁티스트?
Travis Baptiste?
내가 트래비스고
이쪽은 조지요
Yeah, I'm Travis.
This is George.
이웃 사람이 여기서
찾을 수 있다더군요
Your neighbor said
we might find you here.
작년에 마이클 노플릿 씨 밑에서
지붕 고치는 일을 하셨더군요
You guys did some roofing work
for Michael Norfleet last year.
그래요
Yeah, that's right.
그런 건 왜 묻는지 궁금한데요
I wonder why you're asking.
왜 그게 궁금한지 궁금하군요
I wonder if you wonder.
일요일 저녁엔
어디에 계셨죠, 트래비스?
Where were you Sunday night, Travis?
당신 경찰이야?
You a cop?
댁은 살인자인가요?
Are you a killer?
잠깐, 잠깐
Whoa, whoa.
잠깐 쉬어요, 쉬어
내가 처리할게요
Time out, time out.
Let me get that.
- 몽크 씨, 물러나요!
- 병을 깼어요
- Mr. Monk, get back!
- Broken glass.
- 엎드려요! 엎드려!
- 잡아!
- Get down! Get down!
- Take it out!
엎드리라니까요!
Get down, get down!
경찰이다! 경찰!
Cop, cop, the cops!
얼른 튀자
Come on, let's go.
- 여길 뜨자고!
- 꿇어!
- Get out of here!
- Put it down!
모두 마루에 엎드려!
Everyone on the floor now!
경관님, 경관님, 경관님
전 에이드리안 몽크입니다
Officer, officer
Officer, I'm Adrian Monk.
2명의 살인 용의자에 대한
전국 지명 수배를 요청합니다
I want you to put out an APB
on two homicide suspects.
방금 여기서 나간 사람들이요
They just ran outta here.
이름은 트래비스 뱁티스트랑
그 형인 조지입니다, 알았죠? / 예
Their names are Travis Baptiste
and his brother George. Got it? / Yeah.
몽크 씨, 보세요
지갑을 흘렸어요
Mr. Monk, look, he left his wallet.
빈튼 가 109번지면
셰리의 집이네요
109 vinton street.
This is Sherry's house.
여기가 입구고요
Enter here.
누군가가 이자들을 고용했나 봐요
Somebody must have hired them.
뭐예요?
What?
왜 그런 표정을 짓는 거예요?
왜 웃고만 있어요?
Why are you making that face?
Why are you smiling?
그만 해요!
Stop it!
얘야, 괜찮니?
Kid, you all right?
에이드리안, 괜찮아?
Adrian, are you okay?
평생 상처로 남을 거 같아요
He'll be scarred for life.
- 정신적으로요
- 아냐, 이겨낼 거야
- Psychologically.
- Nah, he'll get over it.
뭐라고 하니?
What did he say?
사건을 해결했대요
He said he solved the case.
레오가 어떻게 한 건지 알았대요
He knows how Leo did it.
마이크 노플릿입니다
스토틀마이어 경감님을 뵈러 왔는데요
Mike Norfleet, captain Stottlemeyer
wants to see me.
예, 압니다
Yeah, I know.
끊어야겠네요
I gotta go.
뭔진 몰라도 제 짓은 아니에요
Whatever it is, I didn't do it.
셰리, 반장님
Sherry. Captain.
이게 다 무슨 일입니까?
What's going on?
아, 잘 됐네요
Oh, good!
고쳤군요
You fixed it.
- 새것 같아요
- 선생님, 손대지 마십시오
- It's as good as new.
- Sir, sir, please don't touch that.
증거물이거든요
That's evidence.
무슨 증거물이요?
Evidence of what?
노플릿 씨, 배우자 분의 가정부였던
Mr. Norfleet, you're under arrest
for the murder
글래디스 아퀴노를
살해한 혐의로 체포하겠습니다
of Gladys Aquino,
your wife's housekeeper.
얘야, 네가 스스로 고백한다면
모두의 일이 수월해질 거야
Son, this'll be a lot easier on everyone
if you just confess.
네가 돈을 훔친 거 다 안다
I know you took the money.
말도 안 돼요
쟤 사물함에 있었잖아요
That's crazy. It was in her locker.
주인 말고는 아무도
못 열었을 텐데요
Nobody else could've opened it.
네가 얘 사물함에 모금함을
집어넣었으니 거기 있었던 거지
The cash box was in her locker
because you put it there.
그리고 어떻게 했는지도 알아
And I know how you did it.
사건의 진상은 이렇습니다
Here's what happened.
당신은 트래비스 뱁티스트랑 그 형을
시켜 셰리의 집을 침입하게 했죠
You hired two men,
Travis Baptiste and his brother,
to break into Sherry's house.
어이가 없군
Ridiculous.
이걸 트래비스의 지갑에서 찾았어요
We found this in Travis' wallet.
그런 건 누구든 그릴 수 있소
Anyone could've written that.
사실이에요
It's true.
글자도 인쇄체로 썼고
별다를 것도 없긴 하죠
The letters are printed.
There's nothing special about them.
하지만, 집 주소 쓴 걸 보세요
0을 쓴 방식을요
But look at the house number.
Look at the zero.
사선을 그어 놨어요
There's a little line through it.
어제 한 가질 눈여겨봤지
I noticed something yesterday.
네가 날 사물함에
쑤셔 박았을 때 말이야
When you were stuffing me
into my locker.
그건 정말 제대로 된 애가
할 짓은 아니었지
Which, by the way, wasn't very cool.
그때 보니까 내 자물쇠가
0으로 맞춰져 있더라고
My locker was set to zero.
셰리도 나처럼 늘 0으로
맞춰 두는 걸 기억해 냈지
I remember that Sherry always
set her lock to zero as well.
하지만, 그 전날
But the day before,
티킷 교장 선생님이
모금함을 발견했을 때는
when principal Thicket found the cash box,
0으로 맞춰져 있지 않았어
her lock was not set to zero.
'0'이 중요한 단서입니다
This was all about the zeroes.
이런 식으로 '0'을 쓰는
버릇은 흔치 않거든요
You don't see a zero
written like this very often.
하지만, 어제 당신이
But I saw four of them
셰리한데 이혼수당 수표를 써줄 때
이런 0을 네 개나 쓰더군요
the day before when you were writing
Sherry's alimony check.
난 다른 사람들이 이렇게
'0'을 쓰는 거 많이 봤는데요
I've seen other people
write zeroes like that.
그러면서도 부인 댁의 아래층
도면까지 아는 이는 얼마나 될까요?
True, but how many of them also know
the floor plan to your wife's house?
사건의 진상은 이랬어
Here's what happened.
넌 책 정리를 도와주는 척하면서
When you pretended to help
her with her books,
셰리의 자물쇠를 슬쩍하고는
네 것으로 바꿔 놓았지
you pocketed her lock
and replaced it with yours.
정말 완벽한 계획이었어
It was a perfect plan.
돈을 훔친 다음
You took out the money.
아무도 안 볼 때
돌아와서 모금함을 심어놓은 거야
Then, when nobody was watching,
you came back and planted the cash box.
그 다음에 원래 자물쇠를
걸어 놓은 거지
Then you put her lock back on the locker.
내가 뭐 하러 내 마누라 집에
숨어들어 갈 사람을 고용하겠소?
Why would I hire somebody
to break into her house?
- 딱히 가져와야 할 물건도 없는데
- 아, 맞아요, 동기
- There's nothing in there that I want.
- Ah, yes, the motive.
이 그림이랑 뭔가 관계가
있으려니 했지만
I knew it had something to do
with this painting.
뭔지는 잘 모르겠더군요
But I just couldn't figure out what.
그러다 당신이 이혼수당을 지불하면서
얼마나 진저리를 쳤는지 기억났죠
Then I remembered how you resented
paying all that alimony.
"매달 떼 주기도 정말
지긋지긋하군"이라고 했었죠?
I believe you called it
your monthly pound of flesh.
이혼 수당이요?
Her alimony?
셰리가 재혼하지 않으면
영원히 이혼수당을 대야 하죠
You'd be paying her alimony forever
unless she got remarried.
원래 뭘 훔치거나 누군가를
해칠 계획은 아니었어요
This wasn't about stealing anything
or hurting anybody.
저 사람들 때문이었죠
This was about them.
두 사람을 다시 맺어주려고요
You were fixing them up.
저이도 지미에 대해 알고 있었죠
He knew about Jimmy.
제가 늘 얘길 했으니까요
I talked about him all the time.
지미의 행방을 추적해서
운 좋게 찾아내셨군요
You tracked him down,
and you got lucky.
지미는 독신이었고 게다가
바로 같은 도시에 살고 있었죠
He was single and still living
right here in the city.
하지만, 문제가 있었어요
But you had a problem.
어떻게 둘을 만나게 해 줄까?
How were you gonna get them together?
전화해서 만나라고 얘기할 수 없었죠
You couldn't just call her.
서로 거의 말도 안 하고 있었으니까
You and Sherry were barely speaking.
게다가 당신이 권하면
무조건 싫어할 게 뻔했죠
And she would have resented
any suggestion you made.
그래서 큐피드 노릇을 한 겁니다
So you played cupid.
트래비스 형제를 고용해
집에 숨어들어
You hired Travis and his brother
to break into her house,
그림을 훼손하게 시켰죠
and to deface the painting.
셰리가 아끼는 그림을요
A painting she loved.
틀림없이 복원하고 싶어 할 그림이었죠
One you knew she would want restored.
그러다 제임스에게 그림을
가져가리라 판단한 거예요
You were betting that eventually
she'd bring it to James.
이 도시에서 제일가는
미술 복원가니까요
He is the best art restorer in the city.
일단 만나면 서로 마음이 있음을
알아차리리라 예상했겠죠
They would discover that they
still had feelings for each other.
당신 예상이 맞았어요
And you were right.
참 멋진 얘기지만
Nice story.
아무것도 증명할 수 없을 거요
You can't prove any of it.
아무것도 증명할 수 없을걸
You can't prove any of this.
몽크 같은 이상한 애 얘길 믿어요?
아무나 붙잡고 물어 보세요
Are you gonna believe Adrian Monk?
He's a freak. You can ask anybody.
네 주머니에 있는 걸
다 꺼내봐, 당장
Let's empty out all your pockets.
Come on.
그건 제 돈이에요
That's my money.
트래비스랑 조지는 오늘 아침
라스베이거스에서 잡혔습니다
Travis and George were just
picked up this morning in Las Vegas.
내일이면 여기 도착할 겁니다
They will be here tomorrow.
그 친구들이 다 털어놓을 거요
내 장담하리다
And these boys are gonna talk.
I can promise you that.
그 방 전체에
걔들 지문이 널려 있었거든
Their fingerprints were all over that room.
이 돈은 다과 판매 수익금이다
This money's from the bake sale.
이건 내 필적이고
That's my handwriting.
정직한 에이브 링컨 대통령
옆에 '행운을'이라고 적어 놨지
I wrote "Good luck"
next to honest Abe Lincoln.
내 사무실에서 면담 좀 할까?
Why don't you and I have
a little talk in my office?
미안해
I'm sorry.
정말 미안해
I'm so sorry.
누굴 해칠 의도는 전혀 없었어
Nobody was supposed to get hurt.
글래디스가 왜 있었던 거야?
쉬는 날이었잖아
What was Gladys doing there?
It was supposed to be her day off.
디셔 경위, 구속하게
Lieutenant Disher, book him.
정말 미칠 노릇인 건...
The crazy thing is...
작전이 성공했다는 거야
it worked.
축하해, 여보
Congratulations, darling.
고마워
Thank you.
넌 정말 대단해
You're amazing.
여전히 넌 정말 대단하구나
You're still amazing.
에이드리안
Adrian...
"학교에서 제일 멋진 아이
에이드리안에게" - 친구 셰리
"To Adrian the coolest kid in school."
Your friend Sherry.
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)